welcome to the Microsoft cloud for
sustainability technical Summit
2024 in this session I introduce how to
leverage an endtoend solution for
tracking and Reporting sustainability
specifically designed for smbs my name
is Alexander toich and I'll demonstrate
how sustainability is not just for large
Enterprises let's go over today's agenda
first I'll explain why sustainability
matters for smbs and how easy easy to
implement next we will explore the
features with most of the session
focusing on a live demo lastly I'll
share some useful
resources okay our goal in bringing
sustainability to smbs is to empower
businesses growth while equipping you
with innovate tools to create a positive
environmental and social impact these
features will help you enhance
operational efficiency comply with
regulation and contribute to a more
sustainable
future with this solution you can use
sustainability journals or regular
invoices to capture data manually or
through formulas like emissions by
company region or facility integrated
with other Erp functions if you want
monitor progress with cor cards and
goals using the sustainability R Cent to
track the most important kpis leverage
standard reports and analyzes you to
compare sustainability data with
statistical or general ledger
entries and best of all this solution is
part of Microsoft cloud for
sustainability toil for
snbs the core of Microsoft
sustainability solution for smbs is its
coverage of all three emission scopes
with the focus of reducing carbon
footprint it also track other greenhouse
gases like methan Nitro oxide including
carbon equal
calculations while carbon footprint
measurement is our primary focus in this
release the next B we'll introduce water
and waste management features offering
smbs even much more sustainability
tools looking at the current
capabilities this solution is embedded
within Microsoft SMB Erp solution busy
Center it offers Dynamic calculation if
needed intuitive visualization providing
great collaboration between users and
comprehensive reporting tools you can
use scorecards set goals with built-in
apis allowing integration with partner
Solutions adding new features or
additional reporting
capabilities and each new release we
bring new
features licing and pricing are pretty
straightforward for $70 per user per
month you gain access to all
sustainability features Fe and even the
full Erp solution if needed what does
that mean if you need only
sustainability solution you can start
using only these features but if you
need more for example for your
accounting you can explore the complete
Erp solution at no extra cost and of
course if you're already busy cental
user it will be just a new feature for
you at no extra cost let's review
available
features here's the basic process flow
for recording
emissions the sustainability chart of
account provide a structure framework to
cataloge and log emissions data by scope
or other
groupings you can record emission
through sustainability journals or
purchase invoices when
available if you already have emission
values you can enter them directly but
if you do not have them no problem they
can be calculated through
formulas the system then automatically
calculate carboard equivalent based on
all user gases and your formulas your
setup and logs all data into
sustainability Ledger where it is
accessible for reporting and eventually
for additional API
integration now let's see these features
in action with a short
demo let's begin with this new
sustainability R Center designed
specifically for sustainability
managers this Center Hub brings together
essential
kpis allowing ESG Focus user to access
everything they need without leaving the
r Center although part of full Erp
solution this Ro Center feels
exclusively tailored to own ESG
activities at the top of the screen you
will see daily kpis showing your carbon
footprint compared to previous
day
then we can move to monthly kpis to
display the cumul gas footprint for the
current month with user defined unit of
measure for deeper Insight click see
more to access detailed transaction data
Behind These
kpis
now let's look at the basic insight for
gas
emissions here each gas emission type is
represented with charts showing the
emission ratio by scope hovering over
any scope rals total emissions providing
a clear view of impact and ratio
calculations but there is
more let's review these kpis against our
goals a key area for Progress
tracking here you can track each gas
emissions progress by comparing current
emissions to both targets for the track
period and
Baseline this enable us to assess our
path toward reducing environmental
impact
since uh we are focused on gold progress
here let's see how these values are set
up and calculated in a scorecard
section the score scorecard section is
accessible through the sustainability Ro
Center
easily you'll notice multiple scorecards
each with assigned
owners and I'll open one to review our
goals with these goals we track progress
and kpi
calculations you can configure multiple
goals but only one can be set as a main
goal which is used in the RO center
kpis
now let's go through how these values
are established
we set a baseline
period with start and end dates like
from January to March for a quarterly
goal in our case the system
automatically pulls emissions value for
these Bas on period so everything is
done
automatically next we Define the
reporting period in this case from April
to June again next quarter and the
realtime transactions update current
values in reporting period so that means
whatever you record in a real time it
will be added here we can also set
Target values offering a forecast based
on our
estimates again for each of
us let's now explore where the tracking
starts go back to the chart of
sustainability
accounts this chart organize emissions
data into structure list categorize
sustainability account by attributes
like scope or
other each account has unique identifier
for easy tracking but also description
and some additional
attributes although you are viewing demo
data here this charts so chart of
accounts can be tailored to meet
specific needs just uninstall demo data
and start with your own if you
need like a traditional chart of account
it is built to track data but this time
instead of counting we have
sustainability related data and metrics
organized by
Scopes okay for each gas's emissions you
can view net changes and balances
directly clicking any value takes you to
all related
transactions you will see details such
as whether emissions were recorded
manually or calculated using
formulas like kilowatt hours value in
this example so all these details are
here really easy to be
found the charts includes two key
configuration areas account categories
and subcategories to control system
Behavior categories help group accounts
by scope or set specific emission for
tracking for example carbon only or you
want to track other gases as well and
you can configure formulas here for
calculation if you want to use formulas
such as by default what you have here
for fuel distance installations or
custom formulas what is important to
know Partners can also easily add
specializ formulas if needed so this is
extendable and we added a feature for
users utilize this system as their Erp
solution allowing them to base
calculations on specific expenses or
other General ler transactions so they
just need to enter filtering of
transactions and system will calculate
basing on some
formulas the count sub category
configuration manage emission factors
use in these formulas based on category
settings this is where you add emissions
factor or Mark if emission related to
renewable
energy
now from the chart of sustainability
accounts what you can easily find we can
easily add reports for much more
transfection
details let's start with some of them
let's start with the total emission
report which can be open with the XL out
for additional
Insight the report
display chart comparing emissions ratio
across all Scopes and summarize total
emissions we are using xout because it
provides much more information in one
report
let's close this one and open another
emission by category
report we can further analyze emissions
per period or category here here we can
find in
both chart and table format all gas
emissions per account category so you
can easily compare each of gas emissions
impact based on category further we can
continue with category details and look
at each of accounts grouped by category
and even more we can see an average
admission per category and of course
some other information as
well so we have some built-in reports
not limited only to these to but what if
the user wants more as every company has
its own rules for tracking and Reporting
and not only because of that what if
user want to combine sustainability data
with data from different sources
financial data some other data in this
case if user want customizing report
they can use busy centrals no code
financial reporting
tool this tool is as I said again no
code reporting tool built in in a busy
Central and it can be used for many
different reasons mostly for financial
reports but I show one example of how it
can be used for ESG
reporting just choose the report you
want and click on new financial report
now
when we open this report we can find the
following data emissions by scope one
two or three comparison between current
and past periods one period in past two
periods in past
calculated total carbon offset and also
net impact internal emission fees so all
this information and probably much more
the PO can even integrate social
data like employee then Graphics gender
age and other alongside environmental
metrics and for companies using this Erp
for bookkeeping it enable financial data
integration giving insights like
emissions per dollar earned or including
internal carbon fees in a profit
calculations so you can combine all
these data from absolutely different
sources this tool is incredibly powerful
and here in definitions you can see how
to configure it by yourself
you simply choose what you want to track
and descriptions and select your data
source for instance you can use
sustainability account as a data source
and decide whether to track carbon
equivalent value or apply to carbon
carbon
fee alternatively you might opt to use
statistical accounts for other metrics
or choose General leder accounts you can
also incorporate formulas allowing you
to to pull data from various sources for
your internal calculation so you have
much much more than you can see in these
examples this is really amazing
tool all right let's go back and I'll
walk you through how to record all your
gas
emissions one option is using the
sustainability Journal here you will see
I already have prepopulated journal with
ious sustainability accounts you have
descriptions and everything what is
needed you can also decide whether to
enter missions
manually or to use formulas tied to
different sources for example based on
travel distancing using company car or
perhaps data from hotess taste and so
on it is important to know that if any
information is missing as shown in this
example the system will prevent
incomplete entries prompting you with a
warning so you can complete Data before
moving
forward then another method for
recording emissions is through the
purchasing Voice or order which is
especially conventions if you already
utilized the Erp component of this
system even with numerous active
invoices you will only see those
connected with sustainability and is
here so this is time
saer this setup Save times as it
prevents you from having to re-enter
data into separate documents for
financial and sustainability records so
you can use everything in one document
once you enter financial data in your
purchase document you can easily link it
to sustainability
account you can just find which account
or set up default values for future then
copy the emission values from your
invoice directly into the
system next let's look at how simul
sustainability entries are
integrated with the complete Erp
system if you preview the posting
results you will see Erp standard
information like general ledger entries
vendor entries tax entries so on
everything in the same view but you will
find all the sustainability entries here
this integration save significant time
particularly for snps as you won't need
to go multiple places to record the
review data when you record you can do
everything one place when you review
again when you find one data you can
easily navigate to all other related
data to this transaction so this is
really powerful especially for
smbs with these sustainability
entries you will find specific details
that are ready to be
recorded what is more you can you the
impact of these entries before
finalizing giving you a chance to verify
or correct information before posting
the
setion of course there is a lot more to
explore
but this time we wanted to give you a
quick overview of opportunity available
for SM smbs in the sustainability space
so this is not full presentation this is
just a quick overview what is available
about
sustainability okay to recap this
solution is built on Microsoft cloud and
it is a part of Microsoft cloud for
sustainability for smbs it is embedded
in theam 365 busy Central as solution
offering PR smbs user
experience this is important this is
tailor for smbs with exposed apis and
and an extensive isv ecosystem it is
ready for additional vertical or
horizontal integration so there is no
limitation you can really easily extend
it remember regulation like csrd aren
just for large Enterprises they also
affects
smbs with this tool Microsoft support
businesses of all sizes in their
sustainability Journey so we have tools
for company all sizes if you'd like to
try it you can access and pre-configure
a trial solution with demo data through
this link akms BC trial just go there
use your email and you can easily log
and get in a few minutes everything
ready for
test you can also explore VAR Resources
through the following
links for example you can find complete
manual using akms
BCG and this is really important if you
for example want to try our trial you
will find all details how you can handle
this
solution of course we will be available
for any questions you may have after
this
session thank you